ALI NEHME, Ph.D.

Full Stack Developer

📞 +1 438 334-1206 🔘 ali.nehme@biomedinfo.co 🕏 https://nehmea.github.io/portfolio-fsd/ 🔍 Brossard, Canada

SUMMARY

As a junior full stack developer, I have experience building applications with a variety of languages and frameworks, including JavaScript, Java Spring Boot, React, NodeJS, Python, Django, and PHP. Besides, I have extensive data science experience and a diverse set of soft skills from 10 years of scientific research in a computational biology. I always strive to bring 100% to the work I do. I look forward to joining a creative and hard-working team where I can grow my skills while pushing projects to success.

SELECTED PROJECTS

JobDash

12/2022

A job application dashboard to search, apply, and follow up with application process.

- · Django, React, Python, JavaScript, Azure Cloud Database, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- · Role: backend design, Job Post analyzer, unit testing, CV and applications pages
- https://github.com/CocoScrappy/JobDash
- · https://github.com/CocoScrappy/jobdash-front

Studdy body

11/2022

A school forum for exchanging ideas and solving problems together.

- · ASP.NET, C#, Razor Pages, EF6, MySQL, HTML, Bootstrap, CSS
- · Role: authorization, User, Forums, Posts, Blob storage
- https://github.com/RamiChaouki/StudyBuddy

ChatApp

09/2022

A messaging app/forum similar to Discord with rooms and live messaging.

- · ReactJS, NodeJS, sequelize, MySQL, socket.io, HTML, CSS
- Role: authorization, live messaging, database management, profile management
- https://github.com/nehmea/2022-WDII-chatApp

Commons

A website that can serve as a platform for people to share their possessions.

- · Java Spring Boot, JPA, MySQL, Thymeleaf, Bootstrap, CSS
- Role: project skeleton, database management, authentication and authorization
- ${\color{blue} \bullet \ \ } https://github.com/SpicyRiceTea/HomingPigeonWD1}\\$

HomingPigeon

m 06/2022

A commercial website for selling postcards.

- · PHP, PhpMyAdmin, HTML, CSS
- · Role: products page (add to favourites & cart), product info, profile management
- https://github.com/SpicyRiceTea/HomingPigeonWD1

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

Principal Mentor

STEM-Away

· Designed workshops and oversaw educative projects in bioinformatics.

Computational Biology Consultant

Freelancing

₩ 09/2019 - Ongoing

Helped private and academic teams design projects and perform analysis.

Postdoctoral Researcher in Cancer Genomics

McGill University

🛗 09/2018 - 08/2020 🛛 🗣 Montreal, Canada

- · Designed a workflow to analyze spatial transcriptomics data.
- Assisted colleagues and collaborators on eight projects with bioinformatics analysis

Postdoctoral Researcher in Molecular and Computational Biology

University of Tours

1 09/2016 - 06/2018

▼ Tours, France

- Designed a workflow for horizontal integration of transcriptomics datasets.
- Delivered results on 12 projects using computational and bench methods.
- · Initiated a project for biomarkers discovery in AML using data science and ML.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frameworks

Java Spring	Boot	Django	React	NodeJS
ASP.NET	WPF	Razor Pa	ages	jQuery
Socket IO	JPA	Sequeliz	ze	

Frontend

JavaScript	XAML	HTML	CSS

ThymeLeaf

Backend

Java	PHP	Python	R	C#	Ubuntu

Database

MySQL	MSSQL	phpMyAdmin	Sqlite
-------	-------	------------	--------

Hosting

AWS EC2	AWS RDS	XAMPP

Project Management

Github	Microsoft Office	Trello	JIRA

Data Science

Data Wrangl	ing '	Visualization	Regression
Clustering	PCA	Hypothesis	s Testing

Large data (>100m data points)

SOFT SKILLS

Agile Time		management	Teamwork
Present	ation	Self-learning	Flexiblity

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Developer (A.E.C., 1035 hours, Avg 95%)

John Abbott's College

m 01/2022 - Ongoing

Ph.D. in Bioinformatics and Pathophysiology

Claude Bernard University Lyon 1

1 02/2013 - 11/2015

TRAINING / WORKSHOPS

The Data Science Course 2022: Complete Data Science Bootcamp

Udemy, Ongoing

LANGUAGES

English, French, Arabic